chesstempo.com 2019-03-29

# Chess Tempo Privacy Policy

If you require any more information or have any questions about our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at privacy@chesstempo.com. 

At Chess Tempo, the privacy of our visitors is of extreme importance to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of information that is received and collected by Chess Tempo and how it is used.

### Email Addresses

Chess Tempo requires you enter your email address as part of the user registration process. Under no circumstances is this email address shared with any third parties, including any third parties that may advertise on the Chess Tempo website. 

Email addresses are used as a method to authenticate users if they lose their password, and require a password reset. Chess Tempo will only send you newsletters if you opted in to receive material from Chess Tempo when you signed up. Opting in to receive material will also turn on email notifications for other features such as correspondence game email notifications or comment reply notifications. You can opt out of these and newsletters at any time via your preferences. If you purchased premium membership via Chess Tempo, you may receive emails notifying you of the life cycle of your premium membership, such as when it begins and terminates. These notifications are sent independent of the opt in settings.

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, Chess Tempo makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks and patterns of browser usage, to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. None of this logged information is shared with any third parties

To ensure fair play on the site, the logs may also include information required to help identify duplicate accounts such as specific browser or screen settings.

### Subscription details

If you purchase a premium membership on Chess Tempo, we record the period, and payment amount of your purchase. We do not store credit card details, and all processing and security is handled by our payment partners, Paypal and Stripe. Please refer to their privacy policies for details on their data retention and other privacy details.

### Game and training records

Game and training records are stored and are available publicly. Data extracted from games is also logged and used to help detect cheating and enforce fair play. Game records cannot be deleted as the data is shared by both you and your opponent, however your game history page is removed upon account removal.

Chats are also logged in order to provide a persistent record of chats for users, and to allow us to enforce our terms of service policies on chat abuse.

### Do not track browser settings

We do not current modify our data collection policy based on your browser's Do Not Track setting.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

Chess Tempo does use cookies to store information about visitors preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user accesses or visits, customize Web page content based on visitors browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include Google Adsense.

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on Chess Tempo send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see.

Chess Tempo has no access to or control over cookies that are used by third-party advertisers.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Chess Tempo's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options, however blocking cookies sent to chesstempo.com will prevent you from logging in to your account. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options, however blocking cookies sent to chesstempo.com will prevent you from logging in to your account. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

### Data retention

Data collected by Chess Tempo is kept indexed by your email address and username unless removal is requested.

### Rights provided to EU citizens

If you are a citizen of an EU country, you have the right to request access to your personal data. You also have the right to have that data corrected, updated or deleted. If you would like to exercise those rights, please contact us via the contact methods above. Please note that your data may be transferred outside Europe as part of our operations and data backup requirements.
